<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<orgSettings>
  <orgSetting name="ActivateAdditionalRefreshOfWorkflowConditions" description="Redundant fix for what looks like an issue in a specific version" url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#ActivateAdditionalRefreshOfWorkflowConditions"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="EnableTDSEndpoint" description="&lt;p&gt;This, as it says, allows you to enable the CDS SQL TDS Endpoint, which allows you to use SQL Studio to query your live CDS environment. This is only recent, but is a great addition if you need more complexity in your queries. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MarkMpn!&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mark Carrington&lt;/a&gt; did a great set of posts on it's usage &lt;a href=&quot;https://markcarrington.dev/2020/05/13/cds-t-sql-endpoint-pt-2-first-thoughts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;" url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#EnableTDSEndpoint"></orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="WorkflowXamlValidationErrorReport" description="I can’t find any information on this. Will update when I find out." url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#WorkflowXamlValidationErrorReport"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="TrackAppointmentFromNonOrganizer" description="You can always track a meeting if it was sent from an external user and by default, you can track any appointment where the organiser is a D365 user. This setting prevents the user from tracking an appointment if it is not them organising it." url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#TrackAppointmentsFromNonOrganizer"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="AutoCreateContactOnPromote"
              description="&lt;p&gt;By default, when a user sets regarding within the Outlook app, if any email address is in the To / CC / BCC etc that D365 does not know about, it creates it automatically. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the time this is fine, but consider when your business process requires a lot more data fields to be populated in the contact, this default process will create a contact that hasn’t got what your business needs. Forcing the contact creation away from this automation may be required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users have an option under their personal settings which will mimic this settings, but this does it for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;"
              url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#TrackAppointmentsFromNonOrganizer">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="ChangeDoubleQuoteToSingleQuote"
            description="&lt;p&gt;This setting will do as it says, convert double quotes to single, but is only relevant for the old Knowledgebase Articles in your system, superseded by Knowledge articles that now have an appropriate WYSIWYG editor, this becomes redundant.&lt;/p&gt;"
            url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#ChangeDoubleQuoteToSingleQuote">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="DisableMapiCaching"
            description="&lt;p&gt;This was present to prevent server performance issues, typically seen with on-premise solutions, when results are retrieved from the cache of the server, rather than direct from the database.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            It is unclear if still needed.&lt;/p&gt;"
            url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#DisableMapiCaching">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="EnableActivitiesTimeLinePerfImprovement"
          description="&lt;p&gt;In 2019 Wave 2, October 2019, enhancements were made to the timeline, to improve the density of activities and allowing the user to filter by multiple types etc. Details &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365-release-plan/2019wave2/dynamics365-customer-service/timeline-usability-enhancements&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
          The new timeline can be seen below, which is toggled with EnableActivitiesFeatures described below. This setting toggles improvements to the performance of the new timeline, which may have an impact on your application..&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
          Thought the official line is that this is disabled by default, in any new environment it seems to be enabled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
          &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/image-23.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;"
          url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#EnableActivitiesFeatures">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="EnableActivitiesFeatures"
        description="&lt;p&gt;In 2019 Wave 2, October 2019, enhancements were made to the timeline, to improve the density of activities and allowing the user to filter by multiple types etc. Details &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365-release-plan/2019wave2/dynamics365-customer-service/timeline-usability-enhancements&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
          The new timeline can be seen below, toggled on and off by this setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
          Thought the official line is that this is disabled by default, in any new environment it seems to be enabled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
          &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;https://i2.wp.com/linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/image-23.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;"
        url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#EnableActivitiesFeatures">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="SecuritySettingForEmail"
              description="&lt;p&gt;The majority of emails that a user receives and hence sync to D365 contain HTML to some degree, whether it is simple formatting or full on marketing emails.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;In all scenarios, the interface presents a stripped down version of the email, but formatting etc will be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;There is a risk when these are displayed in all their glory in D365, that parts of the email could be nefarious, including scripts etc that could include phishing or other attacks. Microsoft by default warns the user that this is the case, but allows the user to click through to the content, putting the decision in the users' hands. &lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/image-90.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;
              &lt;p&gt;If you change the setting to 2, the link to the full content is removed&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/image-91.png&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%;height: auto;&quot; &gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Changing the setting to 3 removes the message and always shows the full version of the email&lt;/p&gt;"
    url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#SecuritySettingForEmail">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="ClientDisableTrackingForReplyForwardEmails"
            description="&lt;p&gt;When a user receives a reply to an email that has already been tracked, the reply will also be tracked by default. This is great for keeping the chains of emails all within D365. Unfortunately, this may lead to conversations being tracked that shouldn't and give visibility to sensitive conversations - a manager receiving an email that was a complaint about a particular email that their report sent for example.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Whilst this is mostly a training exercise, it can be quite embarrassing and this setting stops that. It does mean that you could lose out on a part of a conversation and rely on the user to track a response separately.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;This settings, as noted, only works with D365 for Outlook not the App for Outlook. &lt;/p&gt;"
            url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#ClientDisableTrackingForReplyForwardEmails">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="ReassignAllExtendedTimeout"
            description="&lt;p&gt;If you have a security model that relies on a cascade of ownership, when a parent owner is changed, this ownership is also done for children and children of children etc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;This can be a time-consuming process which you can increase the time-out for, possibly temporarily if you have an occasion that required it, though the default 15 minutes is a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;"
            url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#ReassignAllExtendedTimeout">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name ="GrantFullAccessForMergeToMasterOwner"
              description ="&lt;p&gt;Another one of those security options that most people don't know about. I would hazard to guess that most people don't know that the owner of a subordinate record in a merge has the new master shared with them. Mark Carrington has a great explanation of this setting and the next in his blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://markcarrington.dev/2019/08/31/msdyn365-internals-merge-permissions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;The default setting puts a row in the Share table for the original owner, even if it is same as the new owner, which is useful in a lot of cases, but also could break your security model if the owner changes again.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/image-45.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;
              &lt;p&gt;With the setting put to false, the original owner does not have the record shared with them&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://i1.wp.com/linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/image-44.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;"
              url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#GrantFullAccessForMergeToMasterOwner">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="EnableBulkReparent" description="I am not sure this is relevant any more. I assume this is for where you have large datasets and on premise, that could (with cascading) lead to large data changes for each ownership change, but with my environment, I did not notice any change between the two options." url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#EnableBulkReparent"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="MaximumChildUsersCountLimitBeforeUsingJoinForHSM" description="&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, hierarchical security model gives your manager (or managers manager etc) the same access to your data that you have. As a manager with lots of reports, this can cause performance problems, so limiting the maximum unions it makes when deciding on your access makes sense. After this number is reached, an outer join will be used to improve performance..&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;"
  url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#MaximumChildUsersCountLimitBeforeUsingJoinForHSM">
  </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="HierarchyLevelForHierarchyFeature" description="&lt;p&gt;Another security tweak. There are 2 security models that may be in use in your instance, namely managerial or positional security.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Both can take into account a number of managers above you who have the same access to records that you do, which is traditionally 3, and anything above this can cause performance issues. As you can set the hierarchy level on the hierarchy configuration, this setting is now redundant I think, as any change you make to the org setting is not reflected in the setting on the Hierarchy setting screen.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/image.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;"

  url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#HierarchyLevelForHierarchyFeature"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="ActivityConvertDlgCampaignUnchecked" description="&lt;p&gt;When you convert activity to an opportunity, you have the option to populate a related campaign and also record a closed campaign response. This setting implies that you can default the Record a closed campaign response to true, forcing the selection of a campaign, but in my environment, it isn't working.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://linked365.blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/10/image-39.png&quot; style=&quot;width:300px;&quot; &gt;"
  url="https://linked365.blog/2019/11/03/d365-org-db-settings-other/#ActivityConvertDlgCampaignUnchecked"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="ActivityRollupChildRecordLimit" description="&lt;p&gt;This is a new one on me. Activities roll up. You put an email against a contact, the email is available on the account the contact is associated with. This applies to custom entities as well, if you configure the relationship correctly. Inogic has a great post on it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inogic.com/blog/2017/01/configure-rollup-view-for-activities-with-dynamics-crm365/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;p&gt; This setting must have come about to limit this as the numbers where getting too big for some. I have not got the data to do this one justice unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;"
  url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#ActivityRollupChildRecordLimit"> </orgSetting>
  <orgSetting name="AddressBookMaterializedViewsEnabled" description="&lt;p&gt;The description doesnt tie up with the title, and when you google it, this setting revolves around a previous setting, Disable MAPI cache, that was around in CRM 2011 and helped improve performance. Not a lot more I can say.&lt;/p&gt;"
  url="https://linked365.blog/2019/10/01/d365-org-db-settings-email/#AddressBookMaterializedViewsEnabled"> </orgSetting>
</orgSettings>